<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<messages>
    <message id="about-template">
    
        <h1>
            About Witty Wizard Content Management System (CMS)
        </h1>

        <p>
            Witty Wizard CMS is an Open Source Project,
            its a Web Application that uses the Wt Library,
            which is also an Open Source Project,
            its Goal is to create an Easy to Use,
            yet very Secure Web Application that can run multiple Domains under the same Application,
            this allows full utilization of a VPS account to host the Web Application.
        </p>

        <p>
            Witty Wizard CMS is designed in a way where the Back End,
            or Admin Area, is not Required,
            all the Content can be Maintained via FTP or SSH,
            thous reducing its Security Footprint,
            it does not require Apache to run,
            instead it uses a special application called wthttp to run the Wt Application,
            farther reducing its Security Footprint,
            it can also be configured to use SSL Certificates to Authenticate Log ins,
            making it a very secure Web Application.
        </p>

        <p>
            The Core of the Application uses a Menu System which can run in Static or Database mode,
            both methods use Templates,
            which are unique to Wt,
            but are just HTML Markup with added Tags which allow Widgets to be able to be accessed from within the Content,
            this gives the Page Author the Power of C++ using HTML Markup,
            and will give them the power to create very powerful pages with little effort.
            All of the Content and Settings are stored in XML files,
            this makes it easy to maintain without the Traditional Admin Section with a GUI to maintain the Content,
            although the Admin Section will be made Available for all Operations,
            the Goal is to be able to Maintain the Site without it,
            since the Admin Section on any System is its weakest Link when it comes to Security.
        </p>

    </message>
</messages>
